Michael Farquhar GitHub · Portfolio

michaelfarquhar4@gmail.com · +1 519-562-5333 · Windsor, Ontario, Canada

Creative and motivated web developer with 4+ years of experience building intuitive and responsive web applications, primarily proficient in React, TailwindCSS, PHP, and MySQL. Driven by a strong work ethic and a desire for continuous learning. Eager to tackle new challenges and utilize my expertise to make meaningful contributions to a new organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

02/2024 - Present

Self-Employed

Windsor, Ontario

- Developed and maintained responsive WordPress websites for local businesses, implementing SEO, optimizing performance, and ensuring security through various plugins and configurations.
- Manage end-to-end website creation, including web hosting and domain registration, while closely collaborating with clients to meet their business needs.

Full-Stack Web Developer

03/2020 - 10/2023

Digital Media Ltd

Windsor, Ontario

- Developed and maintained over 40+ projects, transforming Adobe XD designs into intuitive and responsive web applications, primarily built with React, PHP and MySQL.
- Collaborated with teams and worked individually, managing projects and timelines using Slack, Zoom, and Asana for efficient and successful delivery.
- Introduced comprehensive internal documentation and implemented new unit tests using PHPUnit, enhancing the code quality for various projects.

Back Shop 04/2015 - 11/2019

Ambassador Golf Club

Windsor, Ontario

 Provided exceptional customer service by managing bag drop, cleaning clubs and carts, and maintaining outdoor services, ensuring an enjoyable experience for all golfers.

EDUCATION

Honours B.Sc. in Computer Information Systems

09/2014 - 04/2019

University of Windsor

Windsor, Ontario

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, MySQL

Web Frameworks: React, Redux, Laravel, SCSS, TailwindCSS, Astro, Firebase

Software & Tools: MS Office, WordPress, VS Code, GitHub, Git, Heroku, Netlify, NPM, Yarn